"NETFLIX
オリジナルシリーズ"
（鳥の鳴き声）
YEAR 3 CLASS REGISTER
（男子生徒）一緒じゃん
KOHARU HIDAKA
（小春(こはる)）あ！
HARUO YAGUCHI
There he is!
あった
３年も また矢口君と
同じクラス
I'm in the same class as Yaguchi
again this year.
（鬼塚(おにづか)）ワタシ １組じゃん
I'm in Class A!
♪〜
ORIGINAL WORK BY RENSUKE OSHIKIRI
〜♪
（ゲーム音）
Come on, Haruo...
（宮尾(みやお)）おいおい春雄
新学期早々またそんなん
学校に持ってきてからに
You brought that stuff into school
so early into the new semester?
A TurboExpress would be
a punishable offense
（春雄）ＰＣエンジンＧＴは
重罪だが―
ゲームボーイなら
罪が軽くなると思うんだがよ
but I think if it's a Game Boy,
it's less of a sin.
何だよその基準
ゲームはゲームだろ？
What kind of rule is that?
A game's a game, right?
In any case, did you hear?
それより聞いたか？
There's a transfer student in Class A.
１組に転入生が
入ってきたらしいけど
かなりの美人ってウワサだぜ
Apparently she's quite the looker!
Wanna take a look after class?
放課後一緒に
見に行かないか？
I'll pass. That's not
where my mind is right now.
いいよ いいよ オレは
それどころじゃないんだよ
最近導入されたスーパー
ストリートファイター２Xを
I'm off to play Super Street Fighter II:
Turbo. It's just been installed.
やりに行くからな！
進化に進化を重ね
進化を遂げて―
The evolution of an evolution...
Of a double-evolved Street Fighter II!
さらに進化したスト２で
俺も進化しなくちゃならねぇ
I, too, must evolve!
Hyper Fighting,
The New Challengers, Turbo...
ターボときて スーパーで…
Ｘか
Guess there's no concept
of a "third" one, huh?
３という概念はないんだなぁ
だから それを言うなや
We don't talk about that.
（チャイム音）
（戸があく音）
Hey, Haruo!
（宮尾）おい 春雄！
行っちまった
And... he's gone.
Miyao...
（鬼塚）宮尾君
（宮尾）うわぁ
You scared me, Onizuka!
んん〜
ビックリした 鬼塚さん
My only happiness in class was
being able to ogle at you...
授業中アナタを視姦するのが
唯一の楽しみだったのに
鬼塚さんは確か
１組になったんだよね？
Right, you got put in Class A, didn't you?
Yeah...
（鬼塚）うん それより
春雄のアホンダラいる？
Anyway, is that idiot Haruo there?
No, he left as soon as the bell rang.
いや チャイムと同時に
すぐ帰ったぜ？
あっそう
I see.
南小卒の人間なら―
There's been quite a surprising return
for us from Minami Elementary.
ビックリする人物が
帰ってきたってのに
（宮尾）あ もしかして
ウワサの転入生？
The transfer student I've heard about?
紹介しないわよ
I won't be introducing you!
あの子相手に恋で勝てる自信
無いからねっ！
I have no confidence in my ability
to beat her in the game of love.
Ah...
ええ…
（春雄）ッフォ〜ア
Alright!
SHIROGANEYA
（小春）うーん
There sure are a lot of
gaming magazines...
ゲームの雑誌って
たくさんあるのね
Hard to pick one...
迷うな
I'd have to get my folks to buy me
a console, first...
っていうかまずゲーム機を
買ってもらわなきゃだよねぇ
（連打音）
（春雄）んんん〜！
（ゲーム音）ジャンケンポン
アーイ…ショ！
くそぉ  誰だよチョキを
連打すれば勝てるなんて―
Just who's been spreading this rumor about
mashing the "scissors" button?
デマ流したの
Yaguchi, you're in such a place
still in your school uniform?
（小春）矢口君 また
こんなところに制服のままで
（春雄）よぉ 日高
Oh, Hidaka!
We really seem to run
into each other a lot.
お前とはホント
街でよく会うな
ドラクエで言ったら
マドハンドくらいの出現率だぞ
If it were Dragon Quest, you'd have
the same appearance rate as a Muddy hand.
We just live in the same area.
（小春）だって生活圏が
一緒なんだもん
So, you even frequent
a kiddy game corner like this?
こんな ちびっ子ゲーム
コーナーにも出没するんだね
こういう
ショッピングセンターも―
Don't take shopping centers so lightly.
Look!
あなどるなかれ　見ろ！
スパ２Ｘがすでに
導入されてんだ
They've already installed
Street Fighter II Turbo.
（ゲーム音）
（小春）こんなところにも
Even here?
No versus-play machine here
対戦台はねーけどここなら
100円で２回できる
but you can play twice for 100 yen.
１人プレイで経験積んで
コマンド覚えたり―
In single-player mode,
you can memorize commands
業の練習ができるぜ
and hone your skills.
さすがに人気ゲームだから
並ぶ事になるがな
It's a popular game, of course,
so you have to wait your turn.
（ゲーム音）
すでに順番待ちの
百円平置きが10枚だぜ
There are already ten 100-yen coins
down as reservations.
Don't you lose track
of who's next?
（小春）どれが自分のか
わからなくならないの？
（春雄）台の前にいるヤツと
後から来たヤツの―
You have to remember the faces
of whoever is before and after you.
顔を覚えておくんだ
You have to remember
where your coin is
あとは自分の百円の位置
特徴を覚えるのも重要だぜ
and also something about it
that makes it special.
（小春）
ゲームひとつやるのに
なんて大変な…
All this trouble
just to play one game...
まあ
ひとつ難点なのは―
Well, there's one downside.
（春雄）１人用で
遊んでいると…
When you're playing
you get this murderous aura
from the people behind
後ろのギャラリーから
早く交代してほしいがための
willing you to hurry up
and finish your turn.
死ね死ねオーラを
出される事だ
（見物人）死ね
死ね死ねオーラを
出される事だ
早く２本とられろ
Hurry up and lose!
（春雄）だからオレは―
And that's why...
変なプレッシャーを
与えないために少し離れて
That's why I keep my distance,
enjoy some popcorn
じゃじゃ丸ポップコーンを
楽しむ寸法さ
and avoid adding to that
weird pressure on the players.
（ゲーム音）
ポンポコポーン
ぽんぽこぽーん
Pop, pop, pop...
Does this make him
childish or mature?
（小春）オトナなんだか
コドモなんだか
（春雄）んぐんぐくそォ〜
Dang!
まだオレは６番目か
チクショウ！
I'm still only sixth in line?
Childish, after all.
（小春）コドモだった
もうダメだ
待ってらんねぇ！
I can't stand it any more!
I'll just go to a bigger arcade
with a faster turnaround time!
回転率が高い対戦台のある―
大型ゲーセンに
行くしかねえぜ！
（春雄）お前
なんでついてきてんの？
Why are you following me?
（小春）ん？
別にいいじゃない
It doesn't matter, does it?
対戦台がメインのゲーセンを
甘く見るなよ
Don't underestimate an arcade
geared toward versus play.
They're packed with people
with killing intent.
闘争心にまみれて殺気だった
輩であふれかえっている
It's a man's battlefield,
pitting pride with will!
プライドと意地が
ぶつかり合う
まさに男の戦場だ
I want to get good at fighting games--
私も格ゲー
上手くなってみたいし
ハンパもんが
ナマほざいてんじゃねえ！
Don't say something like that so lightly!
お前はまず
イーアルカンフーから始めろ
You have to start with Yie-Ar Kung Fu!
（衝突音）
（神崎）あいた
Sonic Ashtray...!
（男Ａ）灰皿ソニックだあー
癇癪(かんしゃく)持ちの
最終必殺技といったところか
The final technique
of an ill-tempered player.
The typical victims are those in the crowd
who aren't paying attention.
アレはだいたい
後ろで見ている―
ギャラリーに当たる事が多い
（死神野郎）テメーこらか！
ハメくさってよー！
You jerk! Quit screwing around!
That hit me, you know!
当て投げ
しやがっただろーっ！
Should be paying more attention.
（ﾒｶﾞﾈ）
投げ受けしないのが
いけないんですぅー
What did you say?
これが大人のケンカだ
This is an adult's fight.
（春雄）スーパー
ストリートファイター２Ｘ
Super Street Fighter II Turbo…
ついにここまで来たか
We've come this far.
もう“Ｘ２”とか“Ｘ３”が
出ても―
Even if they make a Turbo II or Turbo III,
I'll always be along for the ride.
オレは一生ついていくぞ
１プレイ100円だから
慎重になりすぎて―
It's 100 yen per single play,
which can make you anxious
操作が硬くなりがちになるが
and cause some wrong moves...
スパ２で培ってきた技術を
今こそ全力でつぎ込むのだ！
But it's now, of all times
that I need to apply
all of my Street Fighter II expertise!
Ah, man...
（ﾒｶﾞﾈ）あ ちぇー
（春雄）さすが対戦台
As expected with versus-play machines.
It's already my turn.
すぐ番がまわってきたぜ
（プレー音）
Look at this crowd!
このギャラリーの数
うだつのあがらない
このオレが―
For such a no-hoper like me,
stepping onto this big stage
大舞台に立っているようで
たまらねぇ！
is a real thrill!
ONE WIN
TWO WINS
THREE WINS
FOUR WINS
FIVE WINS
SIX WINS
SEVEN WINS
EIGHT WINS
（ガイルさん）春雄　春雄
Haruo... Haruo.
国へ帰っていいか？
Can I go home?
は？　どうした？
Huh? What's wrong?
It happened again.
まただよ
またオレだけ今回も―
Again, I'm the only character
without a new special move.
必殺技の追加が無しだよ
（春雄）オレも今度こそって
思ってたけど
Yes, I thought you'd get one
this time, too...
アンタの強すぎた過去は
よっぽど罪だったようだ
It seems being so overpowered in the past
was your fatal mistake.
But, not to worry.
でも安心しろ
アンタにも皆と平等に―
They gave you a super combo
just like everyone else!
スーパーコンボの存在が
生まれたじゃぇか！
Oh, that? It's difficult to pull off.
（ガイルさん）ああ アレね
コマンド難しいよ？
斜め左下タメ 斜め右下
斜め左下 斜め右上―
Diagonal down-left,
diagonal down-right then down-left,
diagonal up-right, then kick.
キックって感じで
ワケがわからなくないか？
Isn't that too confusing?
Not a problem!
（春雄）大丈夫！
そんなコマンド屁のカッパよ
It's a piece of cake!
（操作音）
NINE WINS
（３人組）
おお 決めやがった
That put an end to it...
Looks like Yaguchi's enjoying it.
（小春）
矢口くん 楽しそう
（男Ｂ）この子も強いけど―
This kid's pretty good
昨日のザンギ使いも
半端なかったな
but that Zangief player yesterday
was no joke, either.
Oh, wasn't it a middle-school girl?
（男Ｃ）
女子中学生くらいの子が
21連勝だったか？
She had a 21-win streak.
（小春）
女子でもそういう子が
いるんだ
So girls like that exist, too!
お？
（ゲーム音）
波動拳！　昇龍拳！
（春雄）出た出た 波動昇龍(はどうしょうりゅう)
There it is, the Hado-Shoryu tactic.
待ちガイルと大差ない
戦法だというのに
It's a strategy similar to Guile-Turtling
but the crowd here doesn't seem
to mind it.
あまり問題視されてない
空気があるんだよな
まあ一生懸命(けんめい)コマンド入力し
戦ってる感があるからだろう
Sure, it seems like a hard fight
since you're constantly inputting moves
単調でつまらん戦い方だぜ
but it's such a stale,
boring fighting style.
やってる本人は本当に
楽しんでいるのか…
Is that player even enjoying
himself like this?
この戦法には距離を
キャラ１人分空けた間隔での
To handle this tactic
keep a one-man distance
from your opponent,
攻防戦を維持
force an exchange of blows.
あとは垂直ジャンプで
昇龍拳を誘発しながら―
While they use
their vertical-jump Shoryukens,
スキを見て攻撃を
チクチク仕掛け
you set up your attacks, one by one.
ゆっくり待ち崩しを
していくのが効果的
It works best, leading this slow
and gradual destruction...
（神埼）ゔ　ゔゔ…
ぐわーっ
This guy's clearly the type
who can't stand losing.
（春雄）コイツは明らかに―
負けたくないタイプの
プレーヤーだな
負けたくない野郎に―
Now, not a chance...
負けるわけには
いかねーんだぜっ！
I can't lose to someone like that!
行くぜ！
Alright!
アンタの長年の無念ッ
I now release you...
今　晴らすっ！
from your years of regret!
TEN WINS
（３人組）おおーっ！
（春雄）どんなもんだい
ガイルさん！
How about that, Guile?
（ガイルさん）
戦いとは無情なものだ
No room for sentiment
in a fight.
But still...
だが オレは負けるわけには
いかなかったんだ
I couldn't afford to lose.
Now that's more like it.
いい顔になったぜアンタ
（男Ａ）10連勝？
-Ten wins?
-This kid's on fire!
（男Ｂ）スゲー野郎だっ！
-Incredible, but a bit creepy.
-A likely Peter Pan.
（男Ｃ）すごいけどキモい！
（男Ａ）ロクな大人に
ならないだろうな
ワハハハ！
（男Ａ）ロクな大人に
ならないだろうな
賛美の声が
心地良いぜ！
I bask in your praise!
And the insults...
（小春）
中傷もまじってるけど
Huh?
あれ？
Yaguchi...
（小春）矢口君
ELEVEN WINS
もし私が強くなったら
どんな顔するんだろ
If I became better at this game...
What would you think then?
もし私が強くなったら
どんな顔するんだろ
（春雄）おい どうした
おらおらおら
Hey, hey, hey.
Not gonna work. Come on!
あー効いてねえぞ
おらぁー！
Make your move!
追ってきたらどうだ
しょーがねぇな
Well, you leave me no option.
Here goes.
ほらよ
あー　もう
Oh, come on...
Come on, come here.
おい　来いよ
ホラホラホラ
That's it, that's it!
いいぞ いいぞ
もうちょい　がんばれ
がんばれ
Almost! Keep going!
あー
Oh, now he'll just keep blocking...
ためてる ためてる
ためてるなぁ
ブランカのスーパーコンボ
グランドシェイプローリングが
Seems he can't execute Blanka's
super combo, the Ground Shave Roll.
出せないようだな
And yet
それに比べオレは無茶な
コマンドなんて何のそのだ！
I know even the craziest combos!
キャラ１人１人のコマンドと
技名を全て覚えてるぜっ！
I've memorized every move
with every character!
（小春）うわぁ
He's trying to beat this newbie
with just his weak punches.
初心者相手に弱パンチのみで
倒そうとしてる
優しいのか
ただただ性格が悪いのか…
Is this him being kind?
Or a feature of his flawed personality?
多分後者ね
Probably the latter.
If we were together, and got married
or something...
もし一緒になって
結婚なんてしたら―
大変そうだなぁ
How troublesome that'd be...
っしゃあ！　12連勝！
A twelve-win streak!
（学生）おい
沼田が来るぞ
Hey, Numata's coming!
（春雄）なっ
Why's this guy always on patrol?
アイツ　なんでしょっちゅう
見回りに来るんだよっ
この連勝記録を放置して
逃げるしかないのか
Do I have no choice but to abandon
my winning streak?
How about I take over?
私が代わってあげようか？
What?
え！？
Yaguchi, you'll get caught
'cause you're in uniform.
（小春）矢口君 制服だから
見つかっちゃうし―
私 私服だから
気づかれないかも
He might not notice me
as I'm in normal clothes.
（春雄）そんな
But, I...
（小春）いいから いいから
It's fine.
Just hide in the bathroom or something.
トイレにでも隠れてれば
いいよ
負けて連勝記録をストップ
させちゃうかもしれないけど
I might lose and cut
your win streak short, though.
（春雄）すまねぇ日高
とにかくここはまかせたぜ
Thanks, Hidaka!
I'll leave it to you, then!
（小春）なんとか
耐えてみせるわ
I have to make it through, somehow.
（鼻）カップルでの
共同プレイか
A tag-team couple...
I'm jealous to death!
（ﾒｶﾞﾈ）うらやましくて
死にたくなるぜ
A... couple?
（小春）カップルか…
まわりからはそう見えるんだ
Is that how others see us?
Ah, I'm a little pleased...
ちょっとうれしいかも
（男Ａ）ガイルスキップ
Guile-skipping?
（男Ｂ）あふれる有頂天！
How brilliant!
（男Ｃ）
ガイルスキップが功を奏した
The Guile-skip worked!
Phew, I managed to win.
ふぅ　なんとか勝てた
（鼻）あどけないプレイ
-Such earnest play...
-Makes me want to cheer her on...
（ﾒｶﾞﾈ）思わず
応援したくなる
（男Ａ）あれ
Huh?
あの子ってもしかして
Isn't that girl...
Could she be...
（男Ｂ）
ああ この前の21連勝の…
The 21-win player from before?
Another challenger...?
（小春）また挑戦者が
え？　どうしたのかな？
I wonder what's wrong...
Seems they don't know who to pick.
キャラ選びに
悩んでるのかな？
え？
-What's that?
-A hidden character?
（見物人達）
何？　なんだアレは？
隠しキャラ？
Isn't that the guy who jumps in before
you fight the Dictator in solo mode?
あれは確か１人用でベガと
戦う前に乱入してくる奴
（小春）ううー　強い
They're good!
手も足もでない！
I can't get in a single attack.
ごめん矢口君
連勝記録守れなかった
Sorry, Yaguchi.
I couldn't protect your streak,
after all.
（見物人）
こんな摩訶不思議な
事をするのは
How mysterious!
Young Miss!
（爺や）お嬢様ぁー
またこんな所で
お遊戯でございますか！
Playing around in a place like this again?
ささ 帰りましょ
Come, now, let's head home.
息抜きもホドホドに…ね
We should take our breaks
in moderation, now...
（春雄）
そうか 負けちまったのは
仕方ねぇ
I see...
I guess losing was unavoidable.
Seems Numata came
just to play games himself
沼田も普通にゲームやりに
きてただけっぽいし
and, well, whatever.
まぁいいさ
I lost to a really pretty girl.
すごくキレーな女の子に
負けちゃった
Huh, a girl?
えっ 女？
キャラ何使ってた？
Which character did she use?
This really scary, violent-looking dude
with a top-knot...
ものすごく横暴そうで
ちょんまげで怖そうなヒト
I see, so a demon-like person...
そうかぁー
鬼みたいなヒトかー
ん？　なんだそいつは？
そんな奴見たことねーぞ！
Wait, what? I've never
seen such a character!
まわりは隠しキャラだって
おどろいてた
Everyone was surprised
about a hidden character.
隠しキャラ！
A hidden character!
ソイツから直接詳しい事を
聞き出さねーと！
I have to ask that player
for the details!
Are they still in the arena?
まだ対戦台にいるのか？
They went home already.
もう帰っちゃったよ
導入されてすぐなのに
そんな事ができるなんて―
Finding out something like that
so soon after the game's release...
ただ者じゃねえっ！
（衝突音）
（春雄）あれ？
Yaguchi!
（小春）矢口君
この感じ
-This feeling...
-Yaguchi!
（小春）矢口君
前にも経験したような
I've felt it before...
（小春）矢口君
（小春）矢口君！
-The feel of that car's hood...
-Yaguchi!
（小春）矢口君！
このボンネットの
感触なんだか懐かしい
Feels so familiar...
このボンネットの
感触なんだか懐かしい
（爺や）なんだか懐かしい
ひき心地
This is nice and familiar.
Isn't it?
Say, now...
おや あそこにいる
お坊ちゃん
That boy there...
お嬢様のお友達だった
お方では？
isn't he a friend of yours,
young Miss?
HI SCORE GIRL
Your class is on cleaning duty?
（鬼塚）４組は掃除当番？
Nice work.
精がでること
（春雄）他のクラスは
もうご帰宅か？
Have the other classes
already gone home?
（宮尾）オレ達も
早く終わらせて帰ろうぜ
Let's finish up quickly
so we can go home, too.
そういえばアンタ
By the way, you.
アレ あの子とは
もう会ったの？
Did you meet with that girl yet?
"That girl"?
あの子？
Yeah, Ono.
ああ 大野さんだろ？
You guys went to the same
elementary school.
春雄たちと同じ小学校だった
Don't you remember?
覚えてないのか？
（春雄）ん？
This one's a total dumbo.
He's completely forgotten!
バカだコイツ
やっぱり忘れてるわ
聞いてよ宮尾君
Listen to this, Miyao.
We all threw a farewell party
when that girl was leaving
その子が転校する日に
お別れ会を催したんだけどさ
このアホだけが贈り物を
持って来なくてさ
and this jerk here
didn't even bring a gift with him.
The whole class was
in utter shock.
クラスの中ではもう
大ヒンシュクよ
ま こんな白状な男に
贈り物をもらっても
Though, well, I'm sure
getting a gift from this heartless boy
大野さんはメーワク
しただろうけどね！
would only have troubled Ono, but...
（宮尾）
そう言うなよ鬼塚さん
春雄が気の毒だ
Don't say such things, Onizuka.
-I'm sure Haruo would--
-Anyway, more importantly!
それよりちょっと
なんでアンタがホウキで
宮尾君がチリトリなのよ！
Why are you sweeping
and Miyao picking up the dirt?
-It should be the other way around!
-Stop picking on them.
フツー逆でしょっ！
（小春）やめなよ
変につっかかるの
That's right, Onizuka.
（宮尾）そうだよ鬼塚さん
早く帰りなよ
Just go home, already.
（エンジン音）
Later, Haruo!
じゃあな 春雄！
（春雄）とうとう
Finally...
Finally, you've returned, Ono.
とうとう帰ってきたか
大野！
My legs are shaking.
足がふるえるぜ
どうしたこったこれは
What's going on?
武者震いだ
I'm trembling!
（なみえ）
どこ行くの 春雄？
Where're you going, Haruo?
Make sure you're back for dinner!
夕飯までに
戻ってらっしゃいよ
でないとゲームの
アダプターを―
Or else I'll hide your game's
power adapter in strange places...
タチの悪い場所に
隠してやるもんね！
Like somewhere haunted...
心霊スポットとか
（戸が閉まる音）
So it's been two years, now...
（春雄）あれから
２年半くらいか
The gaming world evolved
even faster than I'd expected.
ゲーム業界は思った以上に
進化していった
その進化に
置いていかれないように
I like to think I've evolved as well
オレも成長してきたつもりだ
to avoid being left behind.
And you...
オマエは―
どこまで進化した？
How far have you evolved?
And when did you come back?
っていうかいつの間に
帰ってきたんだよ
I know I don't notice these things, but...
それに気づかないオレも
オレだけど
I find myself looking for her.
気づけばアイツの姿を
探してるオレがいる
まぁ それは
今に始まった事じゃないけど
Well, that's nothing new.
あともう１軒あったよな
I think there was one other place.
This...
昔 大野と初めて対戦した
店だ
This is where I first faced Ono.
（見物一同）
ウォォオオオオオオ
（男Ａ）なんて奴だ
これで104連勝だぜ！
She's incredible! That's a 104-win streak!
（見物一同）
ウォォオオオオオオ
104 wins?
（見物一同）
ウォォオオオオオオ
（春雄）１０４！
（プレー音）
（男Ｂ）すげぇ！
Holy cow! You can land
a Screw from that range?
あの距離からスクリューが
入るか？
Get close to that Zangief
and it's like jumping into a vortex.
（男Ｃ）ザンギに近づくと
ほぼ吸い込まれる寸法か！
（男Ａ）敵の攻撃を
She uses a new Banishing Flat move
to cancel her opponent's attacks
新技バニシングフラットで
次々と消し飛ばし―
近づいては投げの嵐っ！
and throw them around!
（男Ｂ）いたいけな
女子の成せる業なのか！？
Is this the true nature
of an innocent girl's power?
（春雄）大野
Ono!
（観衆のざわめき）
If you guard against Zangief's attacks,
（男Ｂ）あのザンギからの
攻撃をガードしたら最後―
he'll grab you on the spot
and give you the Screw.
そのままスクリューに
発展してしまうっ！
（男Ａ）まさに
人間吸引器！
He's like a human vacuum cleaner!
He never loses suction!
（男Ａ）まさに
人間吸引器！
（男Ａ）さらに吸うっ！
Mercilessly sucking!
（男Ｂ）
情け容赦なく吸うっ！
Tons of sucking!
（男Ｃ）吸いまくる！
And then she finishes
（男Ａ）極めつけは
大パンチすかしからの
with a big punch, into the--
（男ＡＢＣ）ファイナル
アトミックバスターだ！
Final Atomic Buster!
（男Ｄ）レバー２回転に
パンチをいつ入力したのか
When did she input two full circles
and two punches?
目にもとまらなかったぞ
It was all a blur!
（春雄）大野…　お前！
Ono... it's really you!
やはり期待を裏切らない
奴だったな
I knew you wouldn't let me down!
久しぶりのご挨拶は
レバーとボタンでだぜ！
I'll greet you after all this time
with a joystick and buttons!
（ゲーム音）
ラウンド１ ファイト！
オレの進化をとくと見よっ！
Witness my evolution!
へ？
どうした大野？
What happened, Ono?
（春雄）なっ
（ﾊｲｴﾅ）いただきっ
Don't mind if I do...
（春雄）ようやく
白黒つけようって時に
Just when I thought
we'd finally settle things.
I don't understand!
ワケが分からねぇ
Leaving the game before it started...
勝負をする前に
去られるなんて屈辱だ！
Humiliating!
（死神野郎）
テメーはめくさって！
Don't mock me!
Then break the throw!
（ﾒｶﾞﾈ）
じゃ投げ受けしろや
Right! I'll just throw you!
（死神野郎）オメーを
今から投げたるわ
うえっ
Not a chance.
（ﾒｶﾞﾈ）やられません
（春雄）大野っ！
Ono!
Darn it...
しまったコイツの１プレイ分
I pressed the multiplayer button
whilst she was on solo play...
２プレイボタンを
押しちまった
ファイナルファイト
Final Fight?
オレが協力プレイに
しちまったから―
Oh, she can't move forwards
because I started co-op play.
進めなくなってるのか
I'm sorry.
ワリィ
（ゲーム音）
ウリャア！　テェイヤ！
What's with her?
（春雄）なんだコイツ
なんでオレとの
スパ２Ｘ対戦を放置して―
Why did she abort the match
with me in Turbo
ファイナルファイトを
やり始めている？
and start playing Final Fight?
もともと無口で―
She was always a quiet
and hard-to-read person, but...
何考えてんのか
分からんヤツだったが
この暴れよう
This rampage.
大野の心情がハガーに
乗り移ってるようだぜ
I can see her feelings
being channeled in-game through Haggar.
って何か怒ってんのか？
Is she mad about something?
Here.
（春雄）ホレ
協力プレイにしちまった分
返すぜ
I'll repay you for stopping
your solo play.
Ouch!
痛でぇっ！
Just... what are you doing?
な 何すんのこのヒトは！
ハガーの動きで
モノ申されたようだ
Sending me messages
through Haggar's movements.
変わってる所が昔から
かわってねぇ
You've still got your weird quirks.
うう 死にそうだ
その肉をくれ！
I'm close to dying...
Gimme that meat--
ああっ！
Hey!
おいオマエ 体力全快の
クセにわざとだろう今のっ！
Look, you!
You had full stamina!
You did that on purpose, didn't you?
Just what is this girl up to? Darn it!
なんのつもりだこの女は
くそっ！
Ono!
（春雄）
大野っ！　ここは電車が
ストップするまで―
I'm going to stay out of harm's way
up on these barrels till the train stops.
タルの上で
避難するべきだぜっ！
Hey!
ちょーっ！
オレに何か恨みでもあるのか
こんちくしょう
Does she hold a grudge against me?
息の合った昔の共同プレイが
ウソみたいだぜっ！
You'd never believe that we used
to be so tight in co-op play...
持ってくんな ！
Don't bring him over here, stay back!
I've got no stamina,
don't bring Andre over here.
体力がないのに
アンドレ持ってくんな！
Ono is...
クソ 大野のヤツ
オレに対して当てつけでも
するようなプレイしやがる
She's playing like she has
some bone to pick with me.
言葉にしなくても―
Even without speaking,
it seems she's laying it on thick.
コイツに罵声(ばせい)を
浴びせられてる気がするぜ
共同プレイを全力で
否定されてる気分だ
It feels like she's totally rejecting
co-op play with me.
I practiced from Champion Edition to Turbo
in preparation for this day.
オレは今日のために
スト２ダッシュから―
スパ２Ｘまで
修行してきたのだ
That was all
それもこれも―
because I dreamed of fighting against you.
オマエと戦う事を夢見て
積み重ねてきた
唯一ライバルと呼べるヤツが
帰ってきたと―
Just when the one person
I could call a rival came home...
嬉しかったのによ
I was so happy!
アレ！　バカか？
What... what's wrong with me?
なんで
目ウルウルさせてんの俺？
Why are my eyes welling up?
くっ　うぅぅっ
（泣き声）
（春雄）
ザンギで111連勝なんて
スゴすぎるよ　大野
A 111-win streak with Zangief...
You're too much, Ono.
オレには到底ムリだ
That'd be unachievable for me.
Even if you had fought me back there,
let's be honest...
さっき対戦したとしても
正直な話―
勝ち目はなかっただろう
I had no chance of winning.
（ガイル）
うわっ〜
Ono...
（春雄）
お前はオレの予想以上に
Have you surpassed my expectations
雲の上の存在に
なっちまったのか？
and reached even further heights?
Was treating you as my rival
ライバルだなんて―
オレの思い上がりも
甚だしかったのか？
just wishful thinking on my part?
Do I even have the right, now,
to sit here
お前を肩を並べて
プレイする資格は―
もはやオレには
and play by your side?
結局ベルガー倒しちまった
We ended up beating Belger.
（爺や）お嬢様〜
Young...
Miss!
Ms. Goda is having a fit
back at the mansion!
業田(ごうだ)先生がお屋敷(やしき)で
御冠(おかんむり)でございますー
ピアノ 水泳 茶道 習字の
お稽古(けいこ)が控えておりまする！
Your piano, swimming, tea,
and penmanship lessons await you.
As ever, seems like things
are still tough for her...
（春雄）
相変わらず色々大変なんだな
（エンジン音）
（小春）あっ
Well, if it gets to be too much,
come find me.
（春雄）
じゃあさ しんどくなったら
逃げてこいよ
I'll take you to some
more obscure arcades.
また妙チクリンなゲーセンに
連れてってやっからよ
今 お前にあげれるもんは
コレしかねぇ
This... this is all
I have to give you now!
Take it!
もらってくれるか？
♪〜
Subtitle translation by
Helen O'Horan
〜♪
（春雄）
普段行かない離れた街とか
たまに行った旅行先とか―
The arcades in a faraway town
or in places you rarely
visit on vacation...
そんなとこで入る
ゲーセンって―
いつもの家のそばの
ゲーセンとは―
They always feel different
from the ones back home, somehow.
何かが違って見えるよなぁ
置いてある筐体は
同じでも―
They have all the same cabinets in them
so why do they feel so different?
違って見えるのは
何でなんだろうなぁ
♪〜
〜♪